As you might have guessed from what you've seen so far this lesson,
根据到目前为止所学的知识 你可能已经猜到了
Funk SVD is a matrix factorization technique
FunkSVD 是一种矩阵分解技巧
that works well for situations like this one,
适合解决这样的情形
where a matrix has a lot of missing values.
即矩阵中缺少很多值
Prior to the Funk SVD method,
在出现 FunkSVD 方法之前
it was commonly used techniques to fill these missing values with zeros.
通常大家采用的技巧是用 0 填充这些缺失的值
But what Simon found to be true was that we could
但是 Simon 发现
actually just ignore all these missing values,
我们可以直接忽略这些缺失的值
and find a way to compute latent factors only using the values we know.
并找到仅仅使用已知值计算潜在因子的方法
In this approach to matrix factorization,
对于这种矩阵分解方法
consider two matrices much like the ones you've seen before.
假设有两个矩阵 看起来和之前的很像
With users and latent factors in one,
一个矩阵是用户 x 潜在因子
and latent factors by movies in the other.
另一个是潜在因子 x 电影
To begin with, we'll just randomly place values into each of these matrices.
首先 在这些矩阵中随机地填充值
This looks good for now.
暂时看起来没问题
Then we search our user item matrix for a rating that already exists.
然后在用户-项目矩阵中搜索已经存在的评分
When we find that rating,
找到一个评分后
we perform the following rule in updating these random values.
按照以下规则更新这些随机值
We'll take the dot product between the row associated with the user,
我们将计算和用户相关的行
and the column associated with the movie.
与和电影相关的列之间的点积
This will give us a prediction for the rating.
得出预测评分
From here, we can calculate the error as
然后计算误差
the difference between the actual and the predicted rating.
即实际评分与预测评分之间的差异
Our goal is to minimize this error across all
我们的目标是通过更改每个矩阵中的权重
known actual values by changing the weights in each matrix.
最小化所有实际值的这个误差
We can do this using gradient descent.
我们可以使用梯度下降法
In the user matrix,
在用户矩阵中
we take the derivative of the error with respect to each value identified by u here.
我们计算误差相对于 U 确定的每个值的导数
Similarly, in the movie matrix,
同理 在电影矩阵中
we take the derivative of the error with respect to
我们计算误差相对于 V 确定的每个值的导数
each value identified by v. Using the chain rule,
然后使用这个链式法则
we find the direction we should move to minimize our error in each matrix.
得出最小化每个矩阵中的误差应该要朝的方向
In each derivative, this portion here,
在每个求导公式里
is just the difference between our actual and predicted value.
这部分表示实际值与预测值之间的差异
We can now use this to update the values in each of our matrices.
我们现在可以使用这个更新每个矩阵中的值
Each of these points in the opposite direction we want to step to minimize our error.
它们与最小化误差的步进方向相反
Let's go through one iteration of gradient descent with the previous matrices.
下面我们对之前的矩阵进行一次梯度下降法迭代运算
This will come in handy.
这些技巧到时候会有用的
To perform our update and the user matrix,
要更新用户矩阵
we will need to look at this row of our user matrix.
我们需要查看用户矩阵的这一行
These values are the u that you saw in the previous equation.
这些值是在之前的方程中看到的 u 值
We also need these values,
我们还需要这些值
which were in the last column of our movie matrix.
它们位于电影矩阵的最后一列
These are the v values you saw in the previous formula.
它们是之前公式里的 v 值
Our new u values will be our current u value,
新 u 值将是当前 u 值
but then we need to update this current value by
不过我们需要更新这个当前值
moving in the opposite direction of the gradient,
更新方法是朝着
which we just found as this term.
这一项代表的梯度的相反方向移动
However, we don't want to move too far in this direction.
但是不能移动太远
So, it's common to use a learning rate to take a small step in this direction.
通常会用一个学习速率朝着这个方向移动一小步
Let's call that alpha and slide that term in front of the direction we're moving here.
称之为 α 将这一项放在要移动的方向前面
Let's put this rule to practice to update the first value.
我们根据这一规则更新第一个值
So, our update says that we take the current value of
更新规则是用当前值 0.8
0.8 and update it by adding to it our learning rate,,
加上后面的部分
which lets just call as 0.01.
学习速率假设为 0.01
This could really be any small number.
它可以是一个很小的数字
Then we multiply this by
用学习速率乘以
two times the difference between the actual and the predicted value,
实际值与预测值之间的差异的两倍
which we found as this earlier.
我们之前已经算出这一项
Finally, we multiply by the corresponding v term on the same latent factor.
最后乘以同一潜在因子的对应 v 项
In this case, the negative 1.2 here.
这里是 -1.2
This gives us a new u value of 0.59.
新的 u 值为 0.59
We could use the same update rule for each of these u values as well,
我们可以对每个 u 值应用相同的更新规则
which give new values of 1.39 and negative 0.23.
得出新的值分别为 1.39 和 -0.23
We could similarly perform these operations for each
我们还可以使用这个方程
of the values in the v matrix with this equation.
对 v 矩阵中的值进行相似的运算
Notice our new values and the u matrix are already having an impact on
注意 u 矩阵中的新值已经对 v 矩阵中的新值
the new values we will see in the B matrix as they appear in our equation here.
产生影响 如这个方程所示
This allows us to update all the v values.
这样我们就能更新所有 v 值
We can replace these updated values into the u and v matrices here,
我们可以用这些更新后的值替换 u 和 v 矩阵中的这些值
and this ends one iteration.
这样的话 一次迭代就结束了
At this point, we look for
接下来
our next non-missing value and update each of our u and v matrices again.
我们将寻找下个非缺失值 并再次更新 u 和 v 矩阵
You perform this technique for
我们需要对所有非缺失值执行这一技巧
all non-missing values and you are likely to go through the matrix multiple times.
并且很有可能迭代矩阵多次
In the upcoming notebook,
在下个 notebook 中
you will implement this technique yourself.
你将自己实施这一技巧
It can be difficult your first time to put an algorithm like this to practice.
第一次练习这种算法可能会比较难
If you get stuck,
如果你遇到问题
the solution notebook is provided,
请参阅解答 notebook
which all walk through following the notebook. Good luck.
我们将在其中演示求解过程加油！